Guide to the Arecibo Ionospheric Observatory and Electrical Engineering reports, 1950-1960.
Arecibo Ionospheric Observatory and Electrical Engineering reports, 1950-1960
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Arecibo Ionospheric Observatory and Electrical Engineering reports, 1950-1960.
16-6-3333
Marshall H.(Marshall Harris) Cohen 1926-,
1 cubic ft.
Published Reports
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Cornell University School of Electrical Engineering technical, scientific and quarterly progress reports, 1950-1960. Arecibo Ionospheric Observatory pamphlet, 1962. Center for Radiophysics and Space Research research reports, 1960-1969; quarterly status reports to the Office of Naval Research, 1963-1969; proposals to Office of Naval Research, 1961-1964; progress report to the National Science Foundation, 1956-1957; and annual report, 1974-1975. The Antenna Laboratory reports from the Dept. of Electrical Engineering, Ohio State University, 1951-1953; report on "High Resolution Studies of Discrete Radio Sources," University of California, San Diego, 1968.
BIOGRAPHICAL NOTE
Astronomer.
COLLECTION DESCRIPTION
Cornell University School of Electrical Engineering technical, scientific and quarterly progress reports, 1950-1960. Arecibo Ionospheric Observatory pamphlet, 1962. Center for Radiophysics and Space Research research reports, 1960-1969; quarterly status reports to the Office of Naval Research, 1963-1969; proposals to Office of Naval Research, 1961-1964; progress report to the National Science Foundation, 1956-1957; and annual report, 1974-1975. The Antenna Laboratory reports from the Dept. of Electrical Engineering, Ohio State University, 1951-1953; report on "High Resolution Studies of Discrete Radio Sources," University of California, San Diego, 1968.
SUBJECTS
Names:
Cohen, Marshall H.1926-,; Arecibo Ionospheric Observatory.; Cornell University.School of Electrical Engineering.; Ohio State University.School of Electrical Engineering.
Subjects:
Radio astronomy--United States--Research.
Form and Genre Terms:
Technical reports.
INFORMATION FOR USERS
CONTAINER LIST
- Cornell University's Center for Radiophysics and Space Research Publications
  - "Radio Astronomy", Mar. 14, 1960 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - "Thermal Radio Emission in an Ionized Gas", Mar. 15, 1960 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - "Scientific Experiments for the Arecibo Radio Observatory", Mar. 31, 1960 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - "Solar Bursts at Meter Wave Lengths", May 31, 1960 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - "Radio Astronomy", June 14, 1960 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - "Range, Declination, and Doppler-Shift Calculations for an Interplanetary Radar", June 30, 1960 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - "Reflection of Radio Waves from the Sun in the Presence of the Magnetic Field of a Sunspot", July 15, 1960 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - "Radio Astronomy", Sept. 14, 1960 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - "Radio Astronomy", Dec. 14, 1960 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - "Radio Astronomy", Mar. 14, 1961 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - "Measurement of Faraday Dispersion in Type III Solar Events", July 31, 1961 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - "Proposal to Office of Naval Research for Extension of Contract Nonr 401 (27) from December 1, 1961 to June 15, 1962", Nov. 13, 1961 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - "Construction of the Department of Defense Ionospheric Research Facility - III", Dec. 30, 1961 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - "Radio Astronomy", Mar. 14, 1962 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - "Radio Astronomy", June 14, 1962 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - "Arecibo Ionospheric Observatory", June 30, 1962 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - "Radio Astronomy", Sept. 14, 1962 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - "Arecibo Ionospheric Observatory", Nov. 1962 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - "Radio Astronomy", Dec. 14, 1962 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - "Arecibo Ionospheric Observatory", Dec. 31, 1962 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - "Proposal to Office of Naval Research for the Continuation of Contract Nonr 401 (27), July 1, 1963 to June 30, 1964", Mar. 25, 1963 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - "Radio Astronomy", Mar. 30, 1963 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - "Proposed Experiments for the Arecibo Ionospheric Observatory", Mar. 30, 1963 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - "Arecibo Ionospheric Observatory", June 30, 1963 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - "Construction of the Department of Defense Ionospheric Research Facility - VI", June 30, 1963 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - "Radio Astronomy", June 30, 1963 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - "Radio Astronomy", Sept. 30, 1963 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - "Arecibo Ionospheric Observatory", Dec. 31, 1963 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - "Quarterly Status Report to the Office of Naval Research on the Measurement of Solar Radio Radiation at 430 Megacycles, ONR Contract Nonr 401 (27), October 1, 1963 through December 31, l963", Jan. 15, 1964 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - "Quarterly Status Report to the Office of Naval Research on the Measurement of Solar Radio Radiation at 430 Megacycles, ONR Contract Nonr 401 (27), January 1, 1964 through March 31, l964", Apr. 1964 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - "Proposal to the Office of Naval Research for the Measurement of Solar Radio Radiation at 430 Megacycles, Continuation of ONR Contract Nonr-401(27), August 1, 1964 through July 31, 1965", Apr. 1, 1964 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - "Arecibo Ionospheric Observatory", June 30, 1964 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - "Quarterly Status Report to the Office of Naval Research on the Measurement of Solar Radio Radiation at 430 Megacycles, ONR Contract Nonr 401 (27), April 1, 1964 through July 31, l964", July 1964 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - "Quarterly Status Report to the Office of Naval Research on the Measurement of Solar Radio Radiation at 430 Megacycles, ONR Contract Nonr 401(27), August 1, 1964 through October 31, l964", Nov. 1964 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - "Arecibo Ionospheric Observatory", Dec. 31, 1964 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - "Quarterly Status Report to the Office of Naval Research on the Measurement of Solar Radiation at 430 Megacycles, ONR Contract Nonr 401 (27), November 1, 1964 through January 31, l965", Mar. 1965 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - "Scintillation Observations Using Intensity Correlations", May 1965 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - "Arecibo Ionospheric Observatory", June 30, 1965 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - "Radiometric Observations of Jupiter, Venus, and Mars at 430 Mc/s", July 1965 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - "Arecibo Ionospheric Observatory", Dec. 31, 1965 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - "Quarterly Status Report to the Office of Naval Research on the Measurement of Solar Radiation at 430 Megacycles, ONR Contract Nonr 401 (27), August 1, 1965 through April 30, l966", May 1966 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - "Final Report to the Office of Naval Research on the Measurement of Solar Radiation at 430 Megacycles, ONR Contract Nonr 401(27)", Nov. 1966 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - "Arecibo Ionospheric Observatory", Jan. 31, 1968 (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - "High Resolution Studies of Discrete Radio Sources" (University of California, San Diego Publication), Sept. 1968 (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - "A High-Performance Line Source Feed for the AIO Spherical Reflector", Feb. 1969 (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - "Arecibo Ionospheric Observatory", Mar. 31, 1969 (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - "Arecibo Ionospheric Observatory", Sept. 30, 1969 (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - "Annual Report, Center for Radiophysics and Space Research, July 1, 1974 - June 30, 1975", July 1975 (Box 1, Folder 17)
- Cornell University's School of Electrical Engineering Publications
  - "Studies on Propagation in the Ionosphere", Mar. 1950 (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - "A Solution for the Path of Radio Waves through the Solar Atmosphere by Elliptic Integrals", Jan. 31, 1954 (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - "The Faraday Effect in the Earth's Ionosphere with Special Reference to Polarization Measurements of Solar Radio Emission", Aug. 30, 1955 (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - "Quarterly Progress Report No. 3", Apr. 20, 1956 (Box 1, Folder 21)
  - "An 8.2 cm Solar Receiver and Heliostat", July 1, 1956 (Box 1, Folder 21)
  - "Solar Radio Noise Final Report", July 1, 1956 (Box 1, Folder 22)
  - "Quarterly Progress Report No. 5", Oct. 20, 1956 (Box 1, Folder 22)
  - "Radio Astronomy Status Report No. 1", Dec. 15, 1956 (Box 1, Folder 22)
  - "Quarterly Progress Report No. 6", Jan. 20, 1957 (Box 1, Folder 23)
  - "Radio Astronomy Status Report No. 2", Mar. 14, 1957 (Box 1, Folder 23)
  - "Quarterly Progress Report No. 7", Apr. 20, 1957 (Box 1, Folder 23)
  - "First Progress Report on National Science Foundation Grant No. G 2549, Polarization Dispersion of the 200 mc Bursts from the Sun for the Year 1 July 1956 to 30 June 1957" (Box 1, Folder 23)
  - "Quarterly Progress Report No. 8", July 20, 1957 (Box 1, Folder 24)
  - "Radio Astronomy Status Report No. 4", Sept. 14, 1957 (Box 1, Folder 24)
  - "Radio Noise and Atmospheric Refraction at VHF and UHF", Oct. 20, 1957 (Box 1, Folder 24)
  - "Radio Astronomy Status Report No. 5", Dec. 14, 1957 (Box 1, Folder 24)
  - "Radio Astronomy Polarization Measurements", Feb. 15, 1958 (Box 1, Folder 25)
  - "Radio Astronomy Status Report No. 6", Mar. 14, 1958 (Box 1, Folder 25)
  - "Radio Astronomy Status Report No. 7", June 14, 1958 (Box 1, Folder 25)
  - "Limitations on the Accuracy of Angular Location of a Radio Star Using Interferometer Techniques", June 30, 1958 (Box 1, Folder 25)
  - "Radio Astronomy Status Report No. 8", Sept. 14, 1958 (Box 1, Folder 26)
  - "Radio Noise and Atmospheric Refraction at VHF and UHF", Sept. 30, 1958 (Box 1, Folder 26)
  - "Radio Astronomy Status Report No. 9", Dec. 14, 1958 (Box 1, Folder 26)
  - "Radio Astronomy Status Report No. 10", Mar. 14, 1959 (Box 1, Folder 27)
  - "Radio Astronomy Status Report No. 11", June 14, 1959 (Box 1, Folder 27)
  - "Antenna Beam Swinging and the Spherical Reflector", Aug. 1, 1959 (Box 1, Folder 27)
  - "Radio Astronomy Status Report No. 12", Sept. 14, 1959 (Box 1, Folder 28)
  - "Reflection of Radio Waves from the Sun", Oct. 15, 1959 (Box 1, Folder 28)
  - "Radio Astronomy Status Report No. 13", Dec. 14, 1959 (Box 1, Folder 28)
  - "Correlator for Noise Signals with Application to 200 mc/s Polarimeter", Jan. 15, 1960 (Box 1, Folder 29)
- Ohio State University's Antenna Laboratory Publications
  - "Theory and Applications of Power Equalizers", May 31, 1951 (Box 1, Folder 30)
  - "Aperture Admittances and Propagation Constants of Metal-Loaded Waveguides", Nov. 2, 1951 (Box 1, Folder 30)
  - "The Aperture Admittance of a Rectangular Waveguide Radiating Into Half-Space", Nov. 14, 1951 (Box 1, Folder 30)
  - "The Normal Modes of Cavity Antennas", Dec. 1, 1952 (Box 1, Folder 31)
  - "An Investigation of Pulsed Radar Systems for Model Measurements", Dec. 1, 1953 (Box 1, Folder 32)